<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title type="text">Arena Tech Blog</title>
  <id>http://techblog.arena.io/blog/atom.xml</id>
  <updated>2018-01-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <link href="http://techblog.arena.io/" />
  <link href="http://techblog.arena.io/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" />
  <generator uri="http://ablog.readthedocs.org" version="0.8.4">ABlog</generator>
  <entry xml:base="http://techblog.arena.io/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">OCaml Operators Cheatsheet</title>
    <id>http://techblog.arena.io/OCaml_Operator_Cheatsheet/</id>
    <updated>2018-01-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2018-01-16T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="http://techblog.arena.io/OCaml_Operator_Cheatsheet/" />
    <author>
      <name>Brendan Long</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the hardest parts of learning OCaml is figuring out what the infix operators do, since they&amp;#8217;re just a string of symbols and you can&amp;#8217;t find them with a Google search. This is my attempt to make a cheatsheet for whenever you&amp;#8217;re wondering what a random series of symbols means. Doing a search on this page should find basic info about any of the common OCaml operators.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://techblog.arena.io/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Responsible Data Science</title>
    <id>http://techblog.arena.io/Responsible_Data_Science/</id>
    <updated>2017-11-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2017-11-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="http://techblog.arena.io/Responsible_Data_Science/" />
    <author>
      <name>Niels Bantilan</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As someone who came into the tech industry from the
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.mailman.columbia.edu/public-health-now/news/breaking-it-down-public-health&quot;&gt;public health field&lt;/a&gt;,
I feel like I naturally seek purpose and social impact in my work. What
does this mean to me as a data scientist? It means that I want to apply
machine learning (ML) to real-world problems in a way that prevents, and
ideally reverses, the widening social disparities that exist today. It’s this
personal mission that drew me to Arena.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://techblog.arena.io/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Painless Model Deployment Using PFA</title>
    <id>http://techblog.arena.io/Painless_PFA/</id>
    <updated>2017-08-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2017-08-24T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="http://techblog.arena.io/Painless_PFA/" />
    <author>
      <name>Brandon Williams</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Like most companies in predictive analytics, Arena has two groups of experts
with differing desires and skill sets: our data scientists constantly design,
test, and refine our algorithms that &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.arena.io/solution.html&quot;&gt;make predictions to improve health care
operations&lt;/a&gt; our engineers build efficient,
scalable infrastructure to productionalize these algorithms, allowing us to
score new input data in real-time. Because of these different goals, there is
often a disconnect between model training and scoring. In the past, when it came
time to move a new algorithm to production, engineers had to manually
reimplement it in another system. Reimplementing anything in software is painful
&amp;#8211; it comes with more bugs, more iteration, new library requirements, and
(because multiple teams are involved) more communication. Any tweaks from the
data science team would require additional work by engineering. This situation
was becoming a hindrance to our productivity, and we knew there had to be a
better way.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://techblog.arena.io/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Arena's Cultural Values at Work</title>
    <id>http://techblog.arena.io/Arenas_Cultural_Values/</id>
    <updated>2017-07-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2017-07-24T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="http://techblog.arena.io/Arenas_Cultural_Values/" />
    <author>
      <name>Vinicius Gravina da Rocha</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At Arena, defining our culture is as important as the quality of the software we
deliver. One emanates from the other. In this blog post I share some of our
cultural values, using stories of real-life situations to illustrate how we
interact with each other on a daily basis: how we go about decision-making, how
we prioritize our work, and what we do when things slip through the cracks.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://techblog.arena.io/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Cuban Conference Crisis</title>
    <id>http://techblog.arena.io/Cuban_Conference_Crisis/</id>
    <updated>2016-12-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2016-12-12T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="http://techblog.arena.io/Cuban_Conference_Crisis/" />
    <author>
      <name>Michelle Micallef</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A year ago I could never have imagined my last night in Havana. I found
myself at the hip Fábrica de Arte Cubano, sitting with a glass of Ron
Santiago on the rocks, listening to &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://bartoszmilewski.com/&quot;&gt;Bartosz Milewski&lt;/a&gt; explain how to achieve determinism in a
concurrent system using a data structure called lattice variables (or
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8dFO5Ir0xqY&quot;&gt;LVars&lt;/a&gt;).  Previously, I
was unhappily programming in Java doing Android Development for a large
tech company. After leaving, I found my current position with a small
company, Arena, that decided to write most of their software in
OCaml. At my company I was introduced &lt;a class=&quot;footnote-reference&quot; href=&quot;#id3&quot; id=&quot;id1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; to functional programming
concepts and the local FP community here in New York City. When my
co-worker, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://rgrinberg.com/&quot;&gt;Rudi&lt;/a&gt;, discovered that there would
be an FP conference, Monad Libre, in Cuba, a country still off limits to
American tourists, I knew I had to go.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://techblog.arena.io/blog/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Go risky on libraries, conservative on infrastructure</title>
    <id>http://techblog.arena.io/Risky_Libraries/</id>
    <updated>2016-12-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2016-12-04T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="http://techblog.arena.io/Risky_Libraries/" />
    <author>
      <name>Trevor Smith, Michelle Micallef</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was a collaboration between Michelle Micallef and Trevor
Smith. Trevor is the VP of engineering at Arena. Michelle is an
engineer at Arena&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting a company off the ground is an exercise in risk management. When
I was hired to build out engineering here at Arena, I was tasked to form
an engineering team and choose our founding technologies. These
decisions had to be made to maximize stability, while allowing us to
innovate quickly. An important choice was what language our engineers
would use. There are many ways a software engineer’s day is impacted by
the language &lt;a class=&quot;footnote-reference&quot; href=&quot;#id2&quot; id=&quot;id1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;. I approached these decisions with a risk management
mindset. The idea is simple and commonplace: you weigh the risks of a
choice compared with the gain to those involved. This pragmatic strategy
was reinforced by a friend who advised me during this time to “go risky
on libraries, conservative on infrastructure.” This is what we did.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
